The day they moved in... Beverly Hills moved out.
The Beverly Hillbillies is a comedy, family film directed by Penelope Spheeris.
Mild-mannered dirt-poor hill-dweller Jed Clampett strikes it
rich when oil is discovered on his property.
At cousin Pearl's insistence, he moves his family to Beverly
Hills to better enjoy his newfound wealth.
Jed Clampett, played by Jim Varney.
Jethro Bodine, played by Diedrich Bader.
Elly May Clampett, played by Erika Eleniak.
Granny, played by Cloris Leachman.
Miss Jane Hathaway, played by Lily Tomlin.
Laura Jackson, played by Lea Thompson.
The Beverly Hillbillies is a 1993 American comedy film directed by Penelope Spheeris, written by Lawrence Konner and Mark Rosenthal, and
starring Jim Varney, Diedrich Bader, Dabney Coleman, Erika Eleniak, Cloris Leachman, Rob Schneider, Lea Thompson and Lily Tomlin.
Based on the television series of the same name (which ran from 1962 to 1971), the film features cameo appearances by Buddy Ebsen (the original Jed Clampett,
in his final motion picture appearance, playing his other starring television role, Detective Barnaby Jones), Dolly Parton and Zsa Zsa Gabor.
The film grossed $57 million worldwide and was panned by critics.
It follows a poor hillbilly named Jed Clampett, who becomes a billionaire after
inadvertently finding crude oil on his property while firing his gun.
The film explores themes of arkansas, oil,
billionaire, hillbilly, beverly hills.
The tone is lighthearted.